Guide to the First Baptist Church of Ithaca records, 1811-2005.
First Baptist Church of Ithaca records,
- Series II. Letters regarding construction of new church
  - Abbot, Chas. F., Nov. 17, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Nov. 18, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Rogers, George D., Nov. 22, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Woolverton, Geo. A., Dec. 2, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Wheeler, Benj. I., Dec. 5, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Jones, Arthur, Dec. 6, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Billy", Dec. 13, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Duncan, S. W., Dec. 17, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Dec. 18, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hedstrom, E. L., Jan. 3, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Childs, H. C., Jan. 15, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bishop, C. C., Jan. 19, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jan. 21, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Schurman, J. G., Jan. 22, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Burr, S. H., Jan. 26, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Andrews, E. Benj., Feb. 7, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Samson, Thomas S., Feb. 14, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bentley, E. T., Feb. 16, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bool Co., Feb. 17, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - John D. Rockefeller, Feb. 24, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Andrews, E. Benj., Feb. 25, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Randolph, Howard F., Feb. 27, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cauldwell, Wm. A., Mar. 1, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bryan, Edwin H., Mar. 31, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Childs, H. C., Apr. 1, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Apr. 2, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gould, L. A., Apr. 15, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Harris, M. D. (Mrs. Robert), May 10, ? (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller, John D., May 15, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller, John D., July 2, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Schurman, J. G., Dec. 19, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bolles, N. A., June 3, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Lane, E. W., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hays, Mrs. Jacob, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - List of donors (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Program for dedication services (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper article mentioning new church (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Series III. Church history
  - Tray with Dr. Jones's picture (Box 21)
  - Jones's memorial service, 1932 (Box 21)
  - Installation Services: Hicks 1949; Jensen 1957 (Box 21)
  - Burning of Mortgage, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Reception for Dr. Boutwell, 1949 (Box 21)
  - Histories of the church (Box 21)
  - Worship Service with Korean Church, 1983 (Box 21)
- Series IV. Renovation, 1970s
  - Correspondence with Historic Ithaca, City of Ithaca, etc. (Box 22)
  - Decision towards renovation (Box 22)
  - Discussion decision (Box 22)
  - Funding of renovation (Box 22)
  - News clippings (Box 22)
  - Publicity (Box 22)
  - Renovations specifications (Box 22)
  - Surveys (Box 22)
  - Job Specifications, 1957, 1977 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous: maps of Ithaca, Site Plans, Campaign Booklets (Box 26)
- Series V. Cash Books
  - Income, 1961-1972 (Box 23)
  - Income, 1971-1972 (Box 23)
  - Income, 1983-1986 (Box 23)
  - Income, 1955-1958 (Box 23)
  - Income, 1978-1982 (Box 23)
  - Income, 1937-1945 (Box 23)
  - Income, 1947-1952 (Box 23)
  - Income, attendance, marriage, funerals, 1957-1966 (Box 23)
  - Expense Records, 1973 (Box 23)
- Series VI. Media
  - Tape 1 of Reverend Christian B. Jensen (8 services), 1368
    Side 1, Channel A - Cantata Mar. 15, 1964
    Side 1, Channel A - Jensen Mar. 22, 1964
    Side 2, Channel A - Jensen Mar. 29, 1964
    Side 2, Channel B - Jensen Apr. 5, 1964
  - Tape 2 of Reverend Christian B. Jensen (8 services), 1369
    Side 1, Channel B - Jensen Dec. 6, 1964
    Side 1, Channel A - Jensen Dec. 13, 1964
    Side 2, Channel A - Jensen Dec. 30, 1964
    Side 2, Channel B - Jensen Dec. 27, 1964
- Series VII. Studies and drawings for remodelling of the First Baptist Church, Ithaca, N.Y., 1930-1932
  These concern alterations to the Chancel, Organ, Vestry, Pulpit, Lectern, Sunday School Quarters, closets, bookcases, etc.
  Architect - Clarence A. Martin, Ithaca, N.Y. in conjunction with George E. Merrill, The American Baptist Home Mission Society, New York, N.Y.
  - 1 Original pencil drawing, 9" x 13" (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 18 Dyelines, 12" x 18" (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 5 Blueprints - 3 16" x 20", 1 18" x 26", 1 20" x 30" (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 6 Tracing cloths - 2 11" x 12", 2 16" x 20", 1 18" x 24", 1 20" x 30" (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 17 Tracing paper sheets - 7 "14" x 18", 4 16" x 18", 6 20" x 30" (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 1 Dyeline, 11" x 15" (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 3 Blueprints 8" x 13" (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 2 Letters from Austin Organ Company (Copies in drawing folder, originals with main collection), Dec. 17, 1931 and Jan. 18, 1932 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 1 Letter from George E. Merrill to Clarence A. Martin, Jan. 16, 1932 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 1 Letter from Clarence A. Martin to George E. Merrill (carbon copies in drawing folder, originals with main collection), Jan. 9, 1932 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 3 8" x 10" graph paper sheets with pencilled notes re parts of the church (Mapcase-folder 1)